Shabir Shabrez Noorani

+33 7 55 09 15 24

11 Rue Georges Dimitrov Bezons-95870, France shabirshabrez1998@gmail.com Linkedin.com

An experienced Business and Strategy Development professional currently pursuing Master of Science in Business Analysis and Consulting from IESEG School of Management, Paris, France. My experience in the industry gives me the ability to adapt in different environments and come up with creative solutions.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

ESS QUE Furniture Works.

Srinagar, J&K -India Mar 2019 – Jul 2021

Operations Analyst.

- Gave recommendations to improve operational efficiency.
- Installed pull system to cut inventory costs by 32%.
- Served as a liaison between 3 departments to increase the flow of products by 8%.
- Changed from vertical integration to horizontal integration which helped in increase of profit by 5%.
- Increased profit margin by 3% by creating relationship with carriers and negotiating rates.

Business Development Analyst Intern.

Oct 2018 – Feb 2019

- Developed and maintained key business relationships with customers.
- Increased customer footfall by 3% through a massive cold calling campaign..
- Initiated referral system gained 14% customer base.

Let's Endorse, Sponsored by SIDBI.

Bijnor, UP -India

Business Analyst Intern.

Feb 2021 – May 2021

- Studied market data of district Bijnor and created a report of how new Medium Small Enterprises can set up.
- Helped create business plan for 120 people and submitted files to banks and EDI (entrepreneurship development of India) to get funding.
- 100 people out of 800 with business acumen were successfully assisted in starting their own enterprise.

Procurement of Supplies, National Institute of Technology.

Srinagar, J&K -India Apr 2018 – Jun 2018

Supply Chain Analyst Intern.

Identified several national suppliers to ensure competitive prices.

- Introduced direct contracting for proprietary goods. Devised peerless route for procurement of supplies taking in consideration topology of Kashmir.
- Costs were reduced by 22%.

VOLUNTARY EXPERIENCE

Ralith Milith (Anti-Drug Society).

Srinagar, J&K -India

Co-Founder/Treasurer.

Jul 2020 – Present

- Co-Founded the anti-drug society to curb drug menace in Kashmir.
- Invited local public figures which included Psychologists, Public speakers, & Sportsperson who helped to increase our reach by 35%.

Kashmir Sahuliyat Voluntary Trust.

Srinagar, J&K -India

Member of Project Manager Cadre.

Oct 2018 - Sep 2019

- Developed and initiated projects, including managing costs, schedule, and performance.
- Helped in reducing expenses by 12% by devising an optimal strategy.

EDUCATION

IÉSEG School of Management.

Paris -France

Master of Business Analysis and Consulting.

Aug 2021 - Present

Supply Chain Management, Project Management, Financial Analysis, Consulting Tools, and Statistics for Consulting.

Islamia College of Science and Commerce.

J&K -India

Bachelor of Business Administrations.

Aug 2015 - Sep 2018

• Accounting, Economics, Strategic Management, and Investment Management.

PROJECTS

Marketing Project, Jammu and Kashmir Bank.

Market Research.

- Researched marketing strategies of various national banks.
- Identified superlative strategies that JK bank can implement.

Risk Management Project, Jammu and Kashmir Bank.

Project Leader.

- Lead a team of 5 members and found problems that lead JK Bank to loses.
- Submitted final report with solutions which was well received.

SKILLS & PERSONAL

Languages: English (Fluent), French (beginner).

IT: R Programming (Intermediatory), Excel & Word (Intermediatory). SQL (Basics), BPMN(Expert), Tableau & Power BI(Intermediatory), Excel VBA(Expert), ERP (Basics), Amazon AWS (Basics).

Interests: Cricket, Cooking, PC Games, and Book Reading.

ONLINE COURSES

Data Analysis with R Programming: Grade achieved 95.43%.

Using Covid-19 Data to Make Supply Chain Logistics in Spreadsheets: Grade achieved 100%

Analyzing Company Performance using Ratios: Grade achieved 83.33%.

R Programming: Grade achieved 92.58%.